Valhalla Rising is a adventure, drama, action film
directed by Nicolas Winding Refn.
Scandinavia, 1,000 AD.
For years, One Eye, a mute warrior of supernatural strength, has
been held prisoner by the Norse chieftain Barde.
Aided by Are, a boy slave, One Eye slays his captor and together he and
Are escape, beginning a journey into the heart of darkness.
On their flight, One Eye and Are board a Viking vessel, but the ship is soon engulfed
by an endless fog that clears only as the crew sights an unknown land.
As the new world reveals its secrets and the Vikings confront their
terrible and bloody fate, One Eye discovers his true self.
One-Eye, played by Mads Mikkelsen.
Kare, played by Gary Lewis.
Gorm, played by Jamie Sives.
Eirik, played by Ewan Stewart.
Barde, played by Alexander Morton.
Pagan Viking Guard, played by Callum Mitchell.
Valhalla Rising is a 2009 English-language Danish period adventure film directed by Nicolas
Winding Refn, co-written by Refn and Roy Jacobsen, and starring Mads Mikkelsen.
The film takes place "most certainly during the twelfth century of our era", and follows a Norse warrior named One-Eye
and a boy as they travel with a band of Christian Crusaders by ship in the hopes of finding the Holy Land.
Instead, they find themselves in North America where they
are assailed by Natives and dark visions.
Shot entirely in Scotland, the title is derived from the combination of Kenneth
Anger's films Scorpio Rising and Lucifer Rising with a Viking theme.
While the film garnered generally positive reviews, it only made back
about $731,613 of its $5.7 million production cost.
The film explores themes of escape, hell, mythology, surreal, gore.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.